

Claudio Cesar de Sá

Curriculum Vitae

SELF PRESENTATION

I am a retired professor of Computer Science in Brazil after teaching for more than 36 years of courses like introduction to programming, symbolic artificial intelligence, mathematical logic, data structures and so much more. My experience involves mostly constraint programming, first-order logic, multi-paradigm programming, and declarative languages (e.g. PROLOG, PICAT, Haskell, Minizinc, C/C++, Python, etc.). Now, I wish to start a new chapter of my career and I'm looking to shift towards helping solving industry-oriented real-world problems using the knowledge and expertise I acquired throughout my life. Positions related to academia are also welcome ⊚!

PERSONAL DETAILS

Address Rua: Ex-Combatentes 125 – Casa E3 – 89.221-103 – Joinville – SC

Country Brazil

Phone (+55) 47 99245 1825

Mails $\underline{ccs1664@gmail.com} - \underline{ccs1664@yahoo.com}$ Site https://claudiocesar.wordpress.com/

GitHub https://github.com/claudiosa/

EDUCATION

Post-doctorate Research (sabbatical year)

2010 - 2010

Université d'Auvergne – Clermont Ferrand – Aurvegne – France

Grant support from Coordination for the Improvement of Higher Education Personnel (CAPES – Brazil). Subject: theoretical aspects of Constraint Programming.

Doctor in Science

Aeronautics Institute of Technology (ITA) – São José dos Campos – SP – Brazil

Grant support from Coordination for the Improvement of Higher Education Personnel (CAPES – Brazil) and Federal University of Alagoas.

Subject: Artificial Intelligence and Theory of Computation.

Master in Science 1982–1987

Federal University of Paraíba (UFPb) – Campina Grande – PB – Brazil Subject: Performance Network.

Bachelor in Electrical Engineering

1977-1981

 $Santa\ Catarina\ State\ University\ (UDESC)\ -\ Joinville\ -\ SC\ -\ Brazil$

Concentration: Electronic and Telecommunication

WORK EXPERIENCE

Upwork

2019 – current

https://www.upwork.com/, on-demand

I had worked as a programmer in languages listed below, my profile is found in: https://www.upwork.com/o/profiles/users/~019017be3783b12815/. I am putting in hold on.

Modal Institute (Instituto Modal)

2020 - 2020

Full-time - https://institutomodal.org.br/

I worked for one month in a project with Prolog, consulting, training a team, and developer.

Lecturer in Computer Science

1986 - 2019

Many universities in Brazil as Computer Science professor

During this period I taught and research in many universities in Brazil. The CNPq site brings a detailed CV about myself in: http://lattes.cnpq.br/2946250323814779 This CV provided is strictly with an academic view. It is ommitted due its size.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Operating System: WINDOWS, LINUX

Programming: $C++(\star\star)$, $C(\star\star\star)$, PYTHON $(\star\star\star)$, PICAT $(\star\star\star\star)$, PROLOG

 $(\star\star\star\star\star)$, EcliPSE $(\star\star\star)$, Haskell $(\star\star\star)$, BASH $(\star\star)$

where a \star : represents domain or fluency

Solvers: Minizinc, OPL, ECLiPSE – Constraint Logic Programming System

, OR-TOOLS, Z3,...

Text Processors: LibreOffice, LATEX, EMACS, ...

Collaborative Tools: GITHUB, OFFICE365, DROPBOX, MEGA, ...

SKILLS

- Symbolic AI
- Declarative Languages
- Constraint Programming
- Modelling in Combinatorial Problems

LANGUAGES

Languages: Portuguese (mother tongue)

English (fluent)

French (fluent – except to write) Spanish (good – except to write)

AVAILBILITY

At this moment, I am interested in a part-time job and remote. For the future, a changing country can be evaluated.

LEISURES

Swimming: according my age!

Active swimmer in open water competitions in Brazil – level advanced in